john-pearce.com 2019-08-08

# Privacy Policy — John Pearce

Our Privacy Policy (Dated 1st May 2018)

We have created this privacy statement for john-pearce.com in order to demonstrate our firm and continuing commitment to the privacy of personal information provided by those visiting and interacting with [John Pearce](https://john-pearce.com/). We hold the privacy of your personal information in the highest regard. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website.

**We recognize the importance of protecting your privacy** and our policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site. This policy will be continuously assessed against new technologies, business practices and our customers’ needs.

**What Information Do We Collect?**

When you visit this web site you may provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis and Web site use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our Web site.

**1\. Personal Information You Choose to Provide**

**Email Information**

If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received by mail and telephone.

**2\. Web Site Use Information**

Similar to other commercial Web sites, our Web site utilizes a standard technology called “cookies” (see explanation below, “What Are Cookies?”) and web server log files to collect information about how our Web site is used. Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Web site, and the Web sites visited just before and just after our Web site.

We also collect email addresses and SMS numbers for the purpose of being able to reach out to members and or people that have entered their details on our webinar registration forms and also on our sales pages where we have specific services available for purchase.

**3\. Browser Push Notification Data**

If you subscribe to the browser “push” notifications on any of our websites, you have the right to delete, access and/or modify the data that is held by our push notification service, iZooto.com.

You can unsubscribe by clicking the settings on any push notification you receive. You can also unsubscribe by following the guidance here: <https://docs.izooto.com/docs/delete-you-data>.

You can delete your data entirely from our records simply by unsubscribing, as described in the preceding paragraph.  Please note that upon unsubscribing, we and iZooto delete all your data that has been held.

If you would like to access or modify the data that is held by our push notification service, you can do so following the guidance here: <https://docs.izooto.com/docs/access-or-modify-your-data>

**How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?**

When subscribing to an email list with us, completing a survey, downloading software tools or information, or buying one of our products, you may be asked to share information about who you are and your contact information. This will include but not be limited to your name, email, and phone number. Where billing information is required we will need an address.

You should understand that any information that you provide via this web site may be used by us to contact you regarding delivery of information, important notifications, promotional material, or any matter relating to john-pearce.com and related services, your request or use of this web site.

This site incorporates the use of Cookies. Cookies are small data text files that are sent from a server computer during a browsing session. Cookies are typically stored on your computers hard drive and are used by Websites to simulate a continuous connection to that site. In order to make our site more responsive to your needs we use cookies to track and manage information relative to your specific interests. In this way we can tailor our site to your needs, deliver a better and more personalised service and track the pages on our site that you visit. The use of cookies automatically identifies your browser to our computers whenever you interact with our site. Your browser options allow you to disable cookies. You should note that if you do disable cookies, you may not be able to access all the services on this site.

Note: A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive or pass on computer viruses.

**Who we share your data with**  
The data processors we use for our business operations who process your data under our control include:  
– Aweber.com for email marketing campaigns  
– Liquidweb.com who provide website hosting  
– Google.com (analytics) who provide website tracking and statistical services  
– Facebook.com who run our social members page  
– GoToWebinar who provide our webinar hosting platform  
– Twilio for SMS messaging  
– Izooto for browser push notifications  
– Skype for group and individual messaging  
– Any other service we might use to communicate with you

We require email and or SMS details so that we can contact individuals about the services and or events that are of interest to the visitors / members. Personally identifiable information or business information will not be shared with parties except as required by law.

Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Website, new services, and special offers we think you will find valuable. You have the right to opt out of our email / SMS list and or make changes to your personal data. You may request copies of any personal data we hold at any time and you can request that this data be deleted entirely from our records by emailing us at the following address:-

**How Do We Use Information We Collect from Cookies?**

As you visit and browse our Web site, the site uses cookies to differentiate you from other users. In some cases, we also use cookies to prevent you from having to log in more than is necessary for security. Cookies, in conjunction with our Web server’s log files, allow us to calculate the aggregate number of people visiting our Web site and which parts of the site are most popular. This helps us gather feedback to constantly improve our Web site and better serve our clients. Cookies do not allow us to gather any personal information about you and we do not intentionally store any personal information that your browser provided to us in your cookies.

**IP Addresses**

IP addresses are used by your computer every time you are connected to the Internet. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network to identify your computer. IP addresses are automatically collected by our web server as part of demographic and profile data known as traffic data so that data (such as the Web pages you request) can be sent to you.

**Sharing and Selling Information**

We **do not** share, sell, lend or lease any of the information that uniquely identify a subscriber (such as email addresses or personal details) with anyone except to the extent it is necessary to process transactions or provide services that you have requested.

**How Can You Access and Correct Your Information?**

You may request access to all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain in our database by emailing us at 

**What About Legally Compelled Disclosure of Information?**

We may disclose information when legally compelled to do so, in other words, when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights. We may also disclose account information when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Terms of Service or to protect the safety of our users and the Public.

**What About Other Web Sites Linked to Our Web Site?**

We are not responsible for the practices employed by Web sites linked to or from our Web site or the information or content contained therein. Often links to other Web sites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our Web site.

Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Website to another web site, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other web site, including web sites, which have a link on our Website, is subject to that Web site’s own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

**Your Consent**

By using our Web site you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to amend this privacy policy at any time with or without notice.

_**Our Commitment To Data Security:**_

Please note that your information will be stored and processed on our computers in the United States. The laws on holding personal data in the United States may be less stringent than the laws of your Country of residence or citizenship. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**Your Right to Opt Out, View, or Make Changes to the Personal Data We Hold**

You can at any time request not to receive further communications from us by either or both email, SMS, FB Messenger or other communications, you may request to view a copy of all the personal data we store, or may request for us to delete all the personal data we hold. You may do this by emailing 

In addition, in the case of SMS and email communications, you will find instructions on how to unsubscribe in each message we send to you.

**Surveys & Contests**

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

**A Special Note About Children**

Children are not eligible to use our services unsupervised and we ask that children (under the age of 14) do not submit any personal information to us. If you are a minor, you can use this service only in conjunction with permission and guidance from your parents or guardians.

**Acquisition or Changes in Ownership**

In the event that the web site (or a substantial portion of its assets) is acquired, your information would be considered part of those assets, and may be part of those assets that are transferred.

**Policy Modifications**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If/when changes are made to this privacy policy, we will email users who have given us permission to do so. We will post any changes here, so be sure to check back periodically. However, please be assured that if the Privacy Policy changes in the future, we will not use the personal information you have submitted to us under this Privacy Policy in a manner that is materially inconsistent with this Privacy Policy, without your prior consent.
